Oh, they have that store in Tokyo, too?
Oh, então aquela loja também tem em Tokyo?
There was always a line. You'd have to wait a whole hour.
Sempre tem fila nela. Tem que esperar uma hora só pra entrar.
Ya made it, Komichi.
Komichi, na horinha!
M-Morning...
B-Bom dia...
Unusual for you to just barely get here in time.
Que esquisito, Akebi-chan, você chegar em cima da hora.
They said Tamura-sensei's running a little late.
Disseram que a Tamura-sensei vai se atrasar um pouco.
Thank goodness.
Que bom, então!
Akebi-san, Akebi-san!
Akebi-san, Akebi-san!
That's me!
O-Oi!
Is it true you're dancing at the after-party?
É verdade que você vai dançar no pós-evento?
Roubai Academy Athletic Festival After-Party Program • Opening Speech • After-Party Planning Committee Vice President (Class 3-4 Takayama Haru) • Stage Program • 1. Quiz Competition: "How Many Do You Know?! Secrets of Roubai Academy" (After-Party Planning Committee) 2. Acoustic Guitar and Singing (Class 2-3 Soumi Ruri) Short Film "As We Accelerate" (Film Research Club) 4. Band Performance (Radical☆Pop) 5. Dance (Drama Club: Akebi Komichi)
Festival de Atletismo da Academia Roubai Pós-evento Programa • Discurso de Abertura • Vice-presidente do Comitê de Planejamento do Pós-evento (Turma 3-4, Takayama Haru) • No Palco • 1. Competição de Quiz: "O Quanto Você Sabe?! Segredos da Academia Roubai" (Comitê de Planejamento do Pós-evento) 2. Guitarra Acústica e Canto (Turma 2-3 Soumi Ruri) Curta-metragem "Conforme Aceleramos" (Clube de Pesquisa Cinematográfica) 4. Apresentação de Banda (Radical☆Pops) 5. Dança (Clube de Teatro: Akebi Komichi)
Oh... Yeah, for the drama club.
Ah... Sim, pelo clube de teatro.
I thought about joining the program, but didn't...
Eu pensei em participar também, mas não fui...
But I'll come watch for sure!
Mas estarei lá para assistir!
I can't wait to see you!
Mal posso esperar para te ver!
I'll be there, too!
Conta comigo lá!
Thanks!
Obrigada!
That's pretty cool, Komichi.
Que legal, Komichi!
What're ya gonna dance to? What song?
Vai dançar o quê? Hein?
I've actually already started practicing.
Na verdade, já comecei a ensaiar...
2. Acoustic Guitar and Singing (Class 2-3 Soumi Ruri) Short Film "As We Accelerate" (Film Research Club) 4. Band Performance (Radical☆Pop) 5. Dance (Drama Club: Akebi Komichi) 6. Catch the Rhythm! Medley of Popular Songs (Brass Band Club) Closing Speech After-Party Planning Committee President (Class 3-2 Hanasato Yuka) Time: After the Athletic Festival's Closing Ceremony Place: Roubai Auditorium
2. Guitarra Acústica e Canto (Turma 2-3 Soumi Ruri) Curta-metragem "Conforme Aceleramos" (Clube de Pesquisa Cinematográfica) 4. Apresentação de Banda (Radical☆Pops) 5. Dança (Clube de Teatro: Akebi Komichi) 6. Segura o Ritmo! Medley de Músicas Populares (Clube de Instrumentos de Sopro) Discurso do Pós-evento Presidente do Comitê de Planejamento do Pós-evento (Turma 3-2, Hanasato Yuka) Horário: Após a Cerimônia de Encerramento do Festival de Atletismo Local: Auditório Roubai
I was practicing this morning before I came here.
Antes de vir pra cá, estava praticando.
Oh, so that's why you came in just under the wire.
Ah, então foi por isso que você chegou em cima da hora.
Well... there it is.
Ah... Aqui está.
I shouldn't butt in.
É melhor não me intrometer.
Hey, Kizaki-san...
Ei, Kizaki-san...
You can play piano, too, right?
Você sabe tocar piano, né?
Huh?
Hã?
I heard you playing the one in the music room when I was cleaning before.
Eu estava limpando a sala de música outro dia e te ouvi tocando.
Plus, there's a piano in your room, right?
Além disso, tem um piano no seu quarto, né?
I bet if you played the piano for Akebi-chan to dance to at the after-party,
No pós-evento, se você tocasse enquanto a Akebi-chan dança,
everyone would love it!
aposto que todo mundo ia adorar!
Huh?
Hã?
You know, I have a CD of the song by Miki-chan that Akebi-chan is dancing to.
Sabe, eu tenho um CD com a música da Miki-chan que a Akebi-chan vai dançar.
Huh?
Quê?!
It's a really nice song with a piano accompaniment!
É uma muito boa com acompanhamento de um piano!
What?!
O quê?!
Yeah, so...
Então, por isso...
H-Hey, I'm just wishing out loud! Don't be mad, okay?
B-Bom, tô só pensando alto! Não precisa ficar brava.
Forget I said anything!
Esquece tudo que eu falei!
Oh, by the way, when I saw Ai in the entryway today—
Ah, é mesmo! Quando vi a Ai na entrada hoje—
I'm not mad!
Não estou brava!
I'm just a little surprised, that's all.
Só fiquei um pouco surpresa.
Really?
Mesmo? Que alívio!
Oh, hey, I made snacks.
Ah, eu fiz uns biscoitos.
Want some?
Quer?
Just one.
Só um.
It's very good.
Está gostoso.
I can't say whether everyone would love it,
Não sei se todos vão gostar,
but I can play the piano.
mas posso tocar... o piano.
A little.
Um pouco.
Episode Eleven Sharing This Time... With Everyone...
Episódio 11 Compartilhando este momento... com todas...
Oops.
Opa...
Receive!
Recepção!
I got it!
É minha!
Ow!
— Ai! — Ai...
A-Are you okay?
V-Vocês estão bem?!
You two really are close, huh?
Vocês se dão bem mesmo, hein?
But that doesn't matter if you can't keep the ball in the air.
Se não conseguem manter a bola no ar, nada disso importa.
This isn't working at all!
Isso não tá dando certo!
These team events are so important, and yet...
Os eventos de equipe são importantes...
They're worth a lot of points, and the final round is the last event of the festival.
Eles valem bastante pontos, e a rodada final é o último evento do festival.
There'll be a lot of people there.
Vai ter muita gente lá...
What should we do?
O que faremos?
It'd be great if we could get all six of us together for a training camp on a day off.
Seria ótimo se pudéssemos juntar nós seis pra um dia de treinamento.
A training camp with all of us?
Um dia de treinamento com todas nós?
I mean, it's a team event.
Sim, times fazem isso.
We need all six of us.
Mas as seis precisam ir.
I was...
Eu...
only thinking about how I could practice myself.
só pensei em como poderia treinar sozinha.
We don't have a place where we can all practice, though.
Não temos nenhum lugar em que possamos treinar.
A place...
Um lugar...
If only there was a gym we could use on a day off.
Se tivéssemos um ginásio pra usar em um dia sem aulas...
Oh!
Ah!
Hello, Komori residence.
Alô, residência dos Komori.
Good evening, Mako-sensei. This is Akebi Komichi.
Boa noite, Mako-sensei. Akebi Komichi falando.
Oh, Komichi-chan! It's been so long!
Ora! Komichi-san, há quanto tempo!
It's good to talk to you again.
Há quanto tempo.
Are you busy at the moment?
Está ocupada no momento?
What's this about? There's no need to be so polite.
Ai, não precisa ser tão formal comigo!
So, how is Roubai Academy?
E como está a Academia Roubai?
It's so much fun!
É muito divertida!
We're having our athletic festival soon.
Logo teremos o Festival de Atletismo.
Oh, that does sound like fun.
Ora, parece ser divertido!
Well, actually... the thing is...
Só que... temos um problema...
You want to bring your classmates to Futaba Elementary's gym to practice?
Você quer levar as suas colegas para o ginásio da Escolinha Futaba para treinar?
Yes, of course you can use the gym.
Claro! Podem usar o ginásio, sim!
Thank—
Obriga—
I'm so happy.
Estou tão feliz...
Huh?
Hã?
You were always talking about how you wanted friends.
Komichi-chan, você sempre me dizia o quanto queria fazer amigos, lembra?
For six years, I only knew you as the only little girl in her class.
Por seis anos, você foi a única menininha da sua turma.
I always told you that I was sure you'd make lots of friends someday,
Eu sempre dizia que tinha certeza de que, algum dia, você faria muitos amigos,
but there was nothing more I could do,
mas eu não podia fazer nada para ajudar,
and that just broke my heart.
e isso me partia o coração.
But I'm so glad.
Mas fico tão feliz agora...
You really did make friends.
Você fez amigos.
That alone...
Só de ouvir isso...
makes me so happy.
meu coração se enche de alegria.
Okay...
É...
Thank you.
Muito obrigada.
How'd it go?
E então?
Mako-sensei said...
A Mako-sensei...
we can use the gym.
deixou usar o ginásio.
W a s h i o H i t o m i
Washio Hitomi
N a w s h i r o Y a s u k o
Nawashiro Yasuko
Oh...
Entendi...
Well, you can't help it if your club's meeting.
Se é pelo seu clube, então não tem jeito.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
Sim. Desculpa.
This sucks.
Poxa vida.
I don't see why our club has to meet on a Sunday.
Por que o nosso clube precisa se reunir justo no domingo?
Right, Hitomi-chan?
Né, Hitomi-chan?
Roubai's volleyball club is the most accomplished of all the clubs.
O Clube de Vôlei da Roubai é o mais bem sucedido de todos os clubes.
What're you writing?
O que você tá escrevendo?
An application.
Um requerimento.
Anyway, Akebi-chan and the other girls sure are motivated, huh?
Mas preciso dizer, a Akebi-chan e as meninas estão bem animadas.
It's just a dumb athletic festival.
É só um Festival de Atletismo idiota.
Aw, don't call it dumb.
Ai, não chama de idiota.
I'm gonna be in the cheer squad along with Akebi-chan, you know...
Estarei na torcida junto da Akebi-chan, sabia?
Huh?
Hã?
So those two can't make it...
Então aquelas duas não vão poder...
Okay!
Beleza!
K i z a k i E r i k a
Kizaki Erika
Oh...
Oh...
Uh-huh.
Ahã.
Komichi's elementary school on Sunday?
Na antiga escolinha da Komichi, no domingo?
Sounds like fun.
Parece uma boa.
Sure, that's fine.
Sim, tudo bem.
Thanks!
Obrigada!
What? Mikan from your parents?
Quê? Tangerinas da sua família?!
That's awesome!
Ai, muito obrigada!
Okay, then, see you tomorrow!
Tá, te vejo amanhã!
Wait, I don't have time to sit here celebrating!
Espera! Não tenho tempo pra ficar comemorando!
I'm gonna get better at volleyball!
Ficarei fera no vôlei!
I wanna go, too.
Também quero ir...
I'm going to practice volleyball.
A onee-chan vai treinar vôlei.
I'm not just going to play around.
Não tô indo pra brincar!
I'll practice, too!
Eu também vou treinar!
It's boring playing in the gym by myself all the time.
É chato brincar sozinha no ginásio toda vez.
I said "playing"...
Ih, falei "brincar"...
She's so squishy!
Ela é tão macia...
I didn't know you were a big sister, Komichi.
Não sabia que você tinha uma irmãzinha.
So smooth...
É tão macia...
Yep.
Sim.
Hey, guys!
Pessoal!
So squishy...
Tão macia...
Usagihara-san!
Usagihara-san!
Morning!
Bom dia!
Morning.
Bom dia.
Nawashiro-san and Washio-san had to go to their club.
A Nawashiro-san e a Washio-san têm reunião do clube delas.
But they'll come in the afternoon.
Mas elas virão à tarde.
Whew, I'm glad we got here in time!
Ufa, chegamos a tempo.
Huh? Wait, how?
Hã? Mas hein?!
You're big!
Que grandona!
What is this?
O que é isto?
What is this little thing?
Que coisinha pequenininha é esta?
Oh, crap!
Ai, caramba!
The bus'll be here any moment!
O ônibus já vai chegar!
Okay, so what the heck happened?
Mas e aí, o que aconteceu?
Well, right after you went back to your room...
Bom, depois que você voltou pro seu quarto...
Request for Permission to Leave the Grounds
Requerimento de Saída do Dormitório
To the Roubai Academy Head of Student Affairs
Para a Diretora de Assuntos Estudantis da Academia Roubai
Names:    Class 1-3, Washio Hitomi
Nomes:    Turma 1-3, Washio Hitomi
Class 1-3 Nawashiro Yasuko
Turma 1-3, Nawashiro Yasuko
[Reasons for Request]
[Motivo do Requerimento]
To practice for the athletic festival volleyball event
Treinar vôlei para o evento de Festival de Atletismo
You really went to all that trouble?
Eita, vocês fizeram tudo isso?
You're totally just ditchin'.
Só estão cabulando a reunião, né?
She told them it was for volleyball practice, same as our club.
Ela disse que era pra treinar vôlei, é como se fosse pro clube.
I didn't lie, and the captain approved.
Eu não menti, e a capitã aprovou.
We're not asking too much, are we?
Não estamos dando trabalho a vocês?
Why are you making that face?
Que cara é essa?
You should be happy that all six of us are together to practice.
Deveria estar feliz por nós seis podermos treinar juntas.
You want to win, don't you?
Quer vencer, não quer?
Yeah.
Sim.
And you said we're going to win, right?
E você não disse que vamos vencer?
Did I say that?
Eu disse isso?
What?! Riri-san?!
Quê?! Riri-san?!
Yeah, I did. You're so gullible, Komichi.
É, eu disse. Você acredita tão fácil nas coisas, Komichi.
Hey! That was mean!
Ai, que maldade!
That was funny!
Foi engraçado!
It looks like a pretty old building.
Parece ser um lugar bem antigo.
Like something you'd see in a movie.
Coisa que você só vê em filme!
I'll go get the key from the teacher.
Eu vou pegar a chave com a professora.
Kao, you take the lead.
Kao, leve elas lá.
It's this way!
É por aqui!
Mako-sensei.
Mako-sensei.
Komichi-chan!
Komichi-chan!
Here you go.
Aqui está.
Thanks.
Obrigada.
The net and balls are in the equipment room.
A rede e as bolas estão na sala dos equipamentos.
Think you can find them?
Consegue encontrá-las sozinha?
We've got girls from the volleyball club. We'll be fine!
Pode deixar comigo e com as meninas do clube de vôlei.
I see. How many friends did you bring?
Entendi. Quantas amigas você trouxe?
Five. And Kao, too.
Cinco. E a Kao, também.
Well, good luck.
Bom treino pra vocês.
I'll be by to peek in on you all later.
Mais tarde eu passo lá para dar uma espiadinha.
Okay!
Tá!
All right, let's get started.
Certo, vamos começar.
Nice one!
Boa!
One more!
Mais uma vez!
Komichi's gotten a lot better.
A Komichi melhorou bastante.
I know. She's better than me now.
Verdade! Ela já está melhor que eu.
Hey, who's in the volleyball club?
E você é do clube de vôlei!
One more, please!
Mais uma vez, por favor!
Are you enjoying it that much?
Tá se divertindo tanto assim?
Yeah.
Sim.
I guess... I'm just so happy.
Acho que... estou bem feliz.
It used to be just me and Kao in this gym,
Costumava ser só eu e a Kao neste ginásio,
but now so many of my classmates are here with me,
mas agora tem várias colegas de turma comigo,
and we're all able to practice together.
e podemos treinar juntas.
It won't help if you're only good when you're here.
Não adianta se você só for boa aqui.
The main event's still ahead.
O evento ainda está por vir.
Yeah, but I'm starting to enjoy this now, too.
Mas devo dizer que estou começando a me divertir também.
Yeah! I haven't been letting the ball drop as much!
Sim! Eu já nem deixo a bola cair tanto assim!
Last run before our break! Let's go!
Vamos mais uma vez antes de dar uma pausa!
Yeah!
Tá!
To a Shining Future
Rumo a um Futuro Radiante
Akebi-chan! Attack!
Akebi-chan! Corta!
Break time!
Intervalo!
I'm burnin' up!
Que calor!
M-Minakami-san!
M-Minakami-san!
This isn't the place to take off your clothes!
Aqui não é lugar pra tirar a roupa!
C'mon, what's the problem?
Ai, qual é?
Wait! Stop!
Não! Não faz isso!
You're all sweaty, too. C'mon, show me whatcha got.
Você também tá toda suada. Mostra pra mim, vai.
I'll change in the locker room!
Eu vou me trocar no vestiário!
Kao-chan, we've got an undresser on our hands!
Kao-chan, temos uma nudista entre nós! Pega ela!
Roger!
Pode deixar!
Hey!
Ei!
Take her shorts off, too!
Vou tirar o short dela!
Huh?!
Hã?!
Now, now, hold still!
Não se mexe!
Wait, seriously, don't!
Sério, não faz isso!
Hold still!
Segura aí!
They saved me...
Fui salva...
No!
Não!
Wha...
Quê?!
You too, Akebi-san?!
Akebi-san, você também?!
Ready to get started now?
Prontas pra recomeçar?
All right...
Muito bem...
Akebi-chan...
Akebi-chan...
Where's the restroom?
Onde fica o banheiro?
The gym restroom is out of order.
O banheiro do ginásio está desativado.
I'll go, too. You can follow me.
Também vou ao banheiro. Vamos juntas.
This school really is old, huh?
Esta escola é bem antiga.
Yeah. It's gonna be closed down once Kao graduates.
Sim. E quando a Kao se formar, será fechada.
Huh?
Hã?
That's why I'm so glad...
É por isso que estou feliz.
that my memories of my elementary school include you guys now.
Agora, vocês estarão nas minhas lembranças da escolinha.
I was scared to use the restroom right up until third grade.
Até o terceiro ano, eu tinha medo de usar o banheiro.
I always asked the teacher to wait by the door for me.
Sempre pedia pra professora esperar na frente da porta.
So now I wish I could tell my younger self
Então, queria poder dizer pra minha versão mais nova
that I'm washing my hands with a friend now.
que hoje...
Akebi-chan...
Akebi-chan...
Well, maybe I'll go peek in on them now.
Bom, acho que vou lá dar uma olhada.
Remember to stretch.
Não esqueça de se alongar.
What should we do about the rotation?
Como vamos fazer rodízio de times?
Let's use rock-paper-scissors to pick teams for now.
Por ora, vamos tirar no jankenpô.
Oh, Mako-sensei!
Ah, Mako-sensei!
Komichi-chan...
Komichi-chan...
You have so many...
Quanta gente...
Come on, Kamimoku-san! You can't sleep here!
Ei, Kamimoku-san! Você não pode dormir aqui!
Oh! They're here!
Ah, elas chegaram!
When I heard Nawashiro-san and Washio-san wouldn't be able to make it,
Quando soube que a Nawashiro-san e a Washio-san não poderiam vir,
I put out a call to everyone in class.
chamei todas da nossa turma.
Onee-chan, lots of people came!
Onee-chan, tá cheio de gente!
Usagihara-san!
Usagihara-san!
Whoa...
Opa!
C'mon, it's too hot.
Para, tá calor.
Yeah.
Sim!
I really... really get to practice with everyone.
Eu vou mesmo treinar com todo mundo...
Sorry, though. Kizaki-san was the only one
Foi mal. Faltou a Kizaki-san, ela não pôde vir porque precisa treinar outra coisa.
Huh?
Hã?
But it's still for the athletic festival, so go easy on her.
Mas é pro Festival de Atletismo, então pega leve com ela.
I messed up again.
Errei de novo.
Fukumoto Miki Music Note Interior
Fukumoto Miki Dentro da Nota Musical
The tempo's so quick, it's hard to play.
O tempo é muito rápido, é difícil de tocar.
I see.
Entendi.
Well, there are lots of things you need to be alone to practice.
Bom, há várias outras coisas que você precisa estar sozinha pra praticar.
Fukumoto Miki Music Note Interior
Fukumoto Miki Dentro da Nota Musical
I know Komichi-san will...
Desde que seja ao lado da Komichi-san...
Sharing this time...
Compartilhei este momento...
with everyone...
com todas...
Here I go!
Lá vai!
Onee-chan, today was fun, wasn't it?
Onee-chan, hoje foi legal, né?
It sure was.
Foi, sim.
Think you'll be able to win at the athletic festival?
Acha que vocês vão vencer o Festival de Atletismo?
Yeah.
Sim.
As long as we're all together.
Se estivermos juntas...
Roubai Academy Athletic Festival
Academia Roubai Festival de Atletismo
We'll win for sure!
Vamos vencer!